federalreserve.gov 2016-12-24

# FRB: Privacy

## Personal Information

We collect NO personal information like names or addresses when you visit our website, or when you visit official Board pages on third-party websites, unless you choose to provide it to us. If you do choose to provide that information to us, it is only used for the purpose for which you gave it to us.

## Information Collected and Stored Automatically

We do collect some technical information. For example, when you browse, read pages, or download information on the Board's website, we automatically gather and store certain technical information about your visit. This information never identifies who you are. The information we collect and store about your visit is listed below:

  * The Internet protocol (IP) address of the domain from which you access the internet (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account) and IP address from which you access our website (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web);
  * The type of browser (for example, Internet Explorer, Firefox) and operating system (Windows, Unix) used to access our site;
  * The date and time you access our site;
  * The pages you visit;
  * The action that you perform (for example, download a document) and whether or not you were successful; and
  * If you linked to the Board's website from another website, the address of that website.

This information is used to help us make the site more useful for you. With this data we learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We also use this data to optimize the site's technical design specifications and/or identify system performance or problem areas. This information is used as a source of anonymous statistical data and is retained for a period of five years; it is shared only when required for law enforcement purposes.

## Cookies

When you visit some websites, their web servers generate pieces of information known as cookies. A cookie is an entry placed in a file on your hard drive by a website that allows it to monitor your use of the website, usually without your knowledge. Some cookies collect personal information to recognize your computer in the future.

The Board's website may use cookies; however, cookies set by or on behalf of the Board do not collect personal information about you, but only your browser "session." The Board generally uses non-persistent "session" cookies. Session cookies are stored temporarily to your computer and last only as long as your web browser is open. Session cookies serve technical purposes like providing seamless navigation through the Board's website. Session cookies do not permanently record data and they are not stored on your computer's hard drive; rather, they are stored in memory and are only available during an active browser session. These cookies do not collect personal information on users, and they are erased as soon as you leave our website. Users that wish to opt-out of the use of these session cookies may do so by changing the settings in their web browser. Instructions on how to make such changes are available at <http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml>

The Board's website uses a "persistent" cookie in very limited situations.  A persistent cookie allows you to create and save customized reports or preference settings for future visits.  Persistent cookies store information on your computer for longer periods.  This type of cookie will remain on your hard drive until it reaches its expiration date or is deleted by you.  The Board uses a persistent cookie in connection with the following Board webpage:

  * [GovDelivery e-mail subscription](https://public.govdelivery.com/accounts/USFRB/subscriber/new), which maintains e-mail addresses that are voluntarily submitted by users so that they will be notified of public events organized by the Federal Reserve. The submitted e-mail address is maintained until it is deleted by the user.

## If You Send Us Personal Information

You may decide to send the Board information, including personally identifiable information. The information you supply--whether through a secure web form, a standard web form, or by sending an e-mail message--is maintained by the Board for the purpose of processing your request or inquiry. The Board also uses the information you supply in other ways to further the Board's mission of maintaining stability and public confidence in the nation's banking system. The Board's website never collects information or creates individual profiles for commercial marketing.

Various employees of the Board may see the information you submit in the course of their official duties. The information may also be shared by the Board with third parties to advance the purpose for which you provide the information, including other federal or state government agencies. For example, if you file a complaint about a financial institution, it may be sent to a financial institution for action, or information may be supplied to the Department of Justice in the event it appears that federal criminal statutes have been violated by an entity you are reporting to the Board. The primary use of personally identifiable information will be to enable the government to contact you in the event we have questions regarding the information you have reported.

Under certain circumstances, the Board may be required by law to disclose information you submit, for example, to respond to a Congressional inquiry or subpoena.

If you register with a Board online mailing list, the information you provide may also be used to send you communications from the Board, or to notify you about updates to our website.

When you choose to send e-mail to the Board you are consenting to the Board using the information provided therein, including personally identifiable information, in accordance with this notice.

## Security

The Board's website is part of a Federal computer system used to accomplish Federal functions. Computer software programs as well as other surveillance methods are used to monitor network traffic on the Board's website for security purposes. By accessing this website, you are expressly consenting to these monitoring activities.

  * For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system employs commercial software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.
  * Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration guidelines.
  * Unauthorized attempts to defeat or circumvent security features; to use the system for other than intended purposes; to deny service to authorized users; to access, obtain, alter, damage, or destroy information; or to otherwise interfere with the system or its operation are strictly prohibited. Evidence of such acts may be disclosed to law enforcement authorities and may result in criminal prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996, as codified at Section 1030 of Title 18 of the United States Code, or other applicable criminal laws.

## **Links to External Websites**

This website links to federal government external websites and to non-federal external websites.  If you click a link to an external website, such as Facebook, Twitter, or YouTube or other external sites, you will leave the Federalreserve.gov site and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners/sponsors of the external website. Non-federal websites do not necessarily operate under the same laws, regulations, or privacy and security policies as federal websites or the Board's website. Links to websites external to the Board's website are indicated by the following icon and an exit pop-up: .

_Links to Federal Government Websites_  
This website links to other federal government websites when those sites contain information that may be beneficial to our users.

_Links to Federal Reserve System Websites_  
As part of the Federal Reserve System, the Board also provides links to information on Federal Reserve Bank websites and other System websites. These sites do not necessarily operate under the same laws, regulations, or privacy and security policies as the Board's website. Links to Federal Reserve System websites are indicated by the following icon: .

_Links to Social Media Third-Party Websites_  
The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System uses certain third-party social media sites as additional means of reaching the public and directing people to [www.federalreserve.gov](http://www.federalreserve.gov/), which is the primary source of information for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. The Board maintains an official page or presence on Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Flickr and LinkedIn. Updates to these pages are generally made during official business hours.

You can access the Board's official pages on Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Flickr, and LinkedIn without having an account or subscribing to services. The Board does not collect any personal information about you, such as your name, address, or online profile, when you access these websites.

As noted above, the Board's privacy policy does not apply on these third party websites and therefore you should familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of the social media site you use. You may access the privacy policy of the social media sites used by the Board at:

[YouTube](javascript:exitWindow\('http://www.youtube.com/FedReserveBoard','ext'\))  | [YouTube privacy](javascript:exitWindow\('http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/','ext'\))

[Flickr](javascript:exitWindow\('http://www.flickr.com/photos/federalreserve/','ext'\))  |  [Flickr privacy](javascript:exitWindow\('http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/flickr/details.html','ext'\))

[LinkedIn](javascript:exitWindow\('https://www.linkedin.com/company/federal-reserve-board/careers?trk=top_nav_careers','ext'\))  | [LinkedIn privacy](javascript:exitWindow\('https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=hb_ft_priv','ext'\))   

_Links to Other Third-Party Websites_  
The site also provides links to other non-federal government third-party websites as a public service. By linking to these external sites, the Board does not imply endorsement of the site's sponsor.

Before linking to an external third-party website, we consider the following criteria:

  * The site clearly relates to and complements existing information, products, and services on the Board's website.
  * The site contains relevant and useful content that will benefit our users.
  * The site contains accurate and timely information.
  * The site provides information at no cost. We do not link to sites whose primary purpose is to sell products or services, except as part of an approved agreement with the Board. (Hotel reservations for Board conferences, for example).

## **Prohibitions**

The Board's website will not link to any website that exhibits hate, bias, or discrimination. Furthermore, the Board's website reserves the right to deny or remove any link that contains misleading information or unsubstantiated claims, or is determined to be in conflict with the website's mission or policies.

## **Disclaimer of Endorsement**

For convenience and informational purposes only, the Board's website provides links to non-government websites. These sites may contain information that is copyrighted with restrictions on reuse. Permission to use copyrighted materials must be obtained from the original source and cannot be obtained from the Board.

The Board is not responsible for the content of external websites linked to or referenced from its website. The Board neither endorses the information, content, presentation, or accuracy nor makes any warranty, express or implied, regarding these external websites. Users should be aware that when they select a link on the Board's website to an external website, they are leaving the Board's site. When users select a link to an outside website, they are leaving the Board's site and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the external website.

  * The Board does not control or guarantee the accuracy, relevance, timeliness, or completeness of information contained on a linked website.
  * The Board does not endorse the organizations sponsoring linked websites and does not endorse the views they express or the products/services they offer.
  * The Board is not responsible for transmissions users receive from linked websites.
  * The Board does not guarantee that external websites comply with Section 508 (accessibility requirements) of the Rehabilitation Act.

## How to Contact Us about the Website

If you have a question about the way your information is used in connection with this website or about the Board's privacy policy and information practices, you may send an online [Privacy Policy Comment](http://www.federalreserve.gov/feedback.cfm) or send a letter to Privacy Comments, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Mail Stop 804, Washington, D.C. 20551.

## Responsibility

The Board's Chief Privacy Officer is responsible for ensuring the Board's implementation of information privacy protections, including the Board's full compliance with federal laws, regulations, and policies relating to information privacy, such as the Privacy Act, that might arise in the administration of this policy.

## Privacy Impact Assessments

The Board complies with the E-Government Act of 2002. The Act requires an agency to conduct a Privacy Impact Assessment (PIA) when developing or buying an information technology system that contains personal information about members of the public. PIAs serve to ensure that privacy protections are addressed throughout the development, design, and deployment of a system by providing an analysis of how personally identifiable information is collected, used, disseminated, and maintained. The following is a list of PIAs published by the Board:

Automated Loan Examination Review Tool (PDF)

Chain Banking Application (PDF)

CHAT Suite of Analysis Tools (PDF)

Community Advisory Council Systems (PDF)

Consumer Complaint and Inquiry Systems (PDF)

Document Management System for Division of Banking Supervision and Regulation and Division of Consumer and Community Affairs (PDF)

eClearance System (PDF)

Electronic Applications System (PDF)

Electronic Workpaper Program (EWP) Supervisory Systems (PDF)

Electronic Governors' Systems (PDF)

Home Mortgage Disclosure Act Data Processing System (PDF)

Fair Lending Tool (PDF)

Federal Reserve Application Name Check System (PDF)

International Training Course On-Line Registration System (PDF)

Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry (PDF)

Office of Inspector General Information Technology Infrastructure Systems (PDF)

Office of the Secretary Correspondence Control System (PDF)

Office of the Secretary Directors Program Database (PDF)

Office of the Secretary Electronic Comments Routing System (PDF)

Office of the Secretary Freedom of Information Act and Privacy Act Case Tracking and Reporting System (PDF)

Oracle Financials (PDF)

Passport and Visa System (PDF)

PeopleClick Recruitment Management System (PDF)

Personal Identity Verification (PIV) Program (PDF)

Research Recruiting Application (PDF)

Secure External Team Space (PDF)

Studies to Develop and Test Consumer Regulatory Disclosures (PDF)

Supervisory Enforcement Actions and Special Examinations Tracking System (PDF)

Taleo Recruiting System (PDF)

Visitor Registration System (PDF)
